Sumesh K Sundaran

UI Developer

SUMMARY

Extensive experience in developing HTML web Internet and Intranet applications using HTML5, XHTML, CSS, Photoshop, jQuery, Content Management Systems with emphasis on semantic HTML, W3C and usability standards.

Develop responsive websites and cross-browser testing across various devices desktop, mobile and tablets.

SKILLS/TOOLS:

Tools/Utilities: HTML5, XHTML, CSS3, jQuery, JavaScripts, Less CSS, Bootstrap,

Business Catalyst, Wordpress, Photoshop, Fireworks, Dreamweaver,

Sublime3.

Operating System: Mac OS X, Windows 7/XP/NT/2000/98/95

EXPERIENCE

Senior UI designer

EQS Web Technologies, Kochi, Kerala (2015 - present)

http://www.eqs.com/

EQS is the leading international technology provider for Investor Relations, Corporate Communications and Compliance. My profile is to develop Investor related websites & Tools, Digital reports, Corporate websites.

Senior UI developer + Project Lead

Innova Technologies, Mumbai, Maharastra (2013 - 2015)

Developed Responsive websites using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Less etc. Created Business Catalyst and Wordpress templates. Quality assured the web pages in various devices like iPad,iPhone,Google Nexus,Samsung Gallexy etc.

- http://multi-purpose-ecommerce-us.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://paper-clip-amaranth-us.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://agent-au.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://olson-us.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://wild-flat-us.mrkdevelopment.com.au/

- http://mist-au.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://flatty-au.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://flat-point-orange-au.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://halcyon-us.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://shield-eu.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://futboldream.com.au/
- http://boldbluewmau.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://eu-designmodo-sample-3-higher-version.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://brushed-au.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://designmodo-sample-3-au.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://parallels-dark-au.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://pratt-au.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://starter-us.mrkdevelopment.com.au/
- http://studio-us.mrkdevelopment.com.au/

Sr. UI Engineer

Bloomberg UTV, Mumbai, Maharastra (2007–2013)

Developed the HTML, XHTML, CSS, Java Script and Jquery for website and microsites (TV shows and Movies) like Market Guru, The Pitch, Autocar, The Assignment etc.

http://www.btvin.com/

Webdesigner

Design Hub, Mumbai, Maharastra (2006–2007)

Designing web layouts, converting JPEG layouts to HTML and Updating Web sites using FTP. Preparing presentations. Making Flash banner.

http://designhub.co.in/

Jn. Officer

Afcons Infrastructure Ltd, Mumbai, Maharastra (2005–2006)

Designing and Maintenance of websites. Day today updation in local site called Intranet. Preparing presentations. Making tutorials using Macromedia Captivate.

http://afcons.com/

Web Designer

Digital Computer Technology, Irinjalakuda, Kerala (2002–2004)

Designing, Maintains of websites.

EDUCATION

B.Com (Bachelor Of Commerce), MG University, Kerala (2002) Plus Two (+12th), Calicut University, Kerala (1997) Board Of Public Examinations (SSLC), Kerala (1995)

CONTACT INFORMATION

e-mail: sumeshmon2006@gmail.com

Phone: **+91 9930087279**

Phone: +91 7034506220

Portfolio: http://sumeshmon.github.io/

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Birth date: 02 May 1980

Gender: Male Nationality: Indian

LANGUAGES

Hindi

English

Malayalam